teleatlas.com 2010-04-14

# Privacy Policy

Online Privacy Policy

Tele Atlas BV, Incl. Web Site Privacy Policy

Tele Atlas BV, Luchthavenweg 48, 5657 EB, Eindhoven, Netherlands and its subsidiaries ("Tele Atlas") respect your privacy. To demonstrate our commitment, we have adopted this web site privacy policy ("Policy") which is designed to inform you about our online collection and use of personal information.  
By using our web site ("Site"), you signify that you have consented to our collecting and using the personal information that you provide to us in accordance with this Policy. You will also be deemed to have read and accepted this Policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.  If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.  
When using our Site, you may provide us information such as your email address, name, title, credit card number, expiration date and mailing address so that we can provide you with our products or services, fulfill your online requests and orders and personalize your experience on our website.  
This policy governs our Site, but does not govern web sites to which we may provide links, because we are not responsible, and can not control the privacy practices or content of those sites. We urge you at all times to use caution when providing information over the internet and suggest that you read the Federal Trade Commission's suggested safety precautions for internet surfing or any equivalent information relevant for your country.

**1\. Types of Information Collected  
**a. Internet Data Collected. We automatically track and collect the following information when you visit our Site: (i) your domain name; and (ii) the web pages on our Site that you view or visit (collectively "Internet Data"). Internet Data is anonymous and statistical information that does not personally identify you but is helpful for marketing purposes and for improving your experience on the Site.  
We may also use "cookies " or other tracking means to personalize your online experience, to ensure that you do not see temporary content (e.g. Flash content or banner notices) repeatedly and to store your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Site. These "cookies" are designed to lapse when your visit to our Site ends or your web browser is closed. It is possible for you to disable cookies within your specific browser options, although it may impair your use of our Site.

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any individual identifying information you submit while on our site. 

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies.  We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. [http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.mspx](http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.mspx)

Cookies are used to keep track of user choice of language and other site specific settings. We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don't have to enter it more than once.  Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. 

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, and service providers is not covered by our privacy statement.  We do not have access or control over these cookies.  Our partners, affiliates, and service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.   
b. Individual Identifying Information Collected. In order for you to purchase products that we offer via the Site, we require you to provide us with information that personally identifies you to enable us to complete the transaction ("Identifying Information"). Identifying Information may include Contact Data (such as your name, title, company, mailing and e-mail addresses) and Financial Data (such as your account or credit card number).  
While using our Contentlink portion of the site, you are able to add users to the portal in order to allow them to have use of the Contentlink portal.  The information we collect from you is a username, password, name and email address.  We use this information for the sole purpose of setting up a user account in order to allow them to have individual access to this part of the site.  
If you communicate with us by e-mail or complete online forms, surveys or contest entries, any information provided in such communication may be collected as Identifying Information.  
You may choose not to provide us with any Identifying Information. In such an event, you can still access and use much of the Site; however you will not be able to access and use those portions of the Site that require your Identifying Information.

| 

**2\. Use of Information Collected**

We may use Contact Data to e-mail, mail or call you via telephone to provide you with information about our company or our products or services. If you would like to receive such information from us, please click the relevant button [or tick the relevant box] when entering your contact details on our Site. We use your Financial Data to qualify and bill you for the products and services you have purchased on our Site. We may use your Contact Data to customize and tailor your experience on the Site; displaying content that we think may interest you according to your preferences. We may use your Contact Data for shipping product.

_Newsletters_   
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you.  Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe.  Please see the "Choice and Opt-out" section.

**3\. Sharing of Identifying Information**

We may share Identifying Information about you with other companies or people when: (a) We have your consent to share the information; (b) We need to share the information in order to provide the product or service you have requested; (c) We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of us to provide you with a product or service that you requested. Unless we tell you differently, these companies do not have any right to use the Identifying Information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us.   
Third parties that receive your Identifying Information may be based in other countries that do not have the same level of data protection as your country. By providing your Identifying Information on our Site, you consent to your Identifying Information being shared with third parties in this way.

**4\. Confidentiality and Security of Identifying Information**   
We reserve the right to disclose your Identifying information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

We will keep your Identifying Information private unless such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with a court order or other legal process; (b) protect our rights or property; or (c) enforce any agreement between us and you. We provide you with the capability to transmit your Identifying Information via secured and encrypted channels if you use a similarly equipped web browser, and your Identifying Information is stored on our servers that are not accessible by third parties.

**5\. User Ability to Access, Update and Correct Identifying Information  
**Updating/Accessing/Amending/Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If your Identifying Information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or deactivate it by making the change, or having your company's ContentLink administrator, make the change, on the administration tab of your Tele Atlas ContentLink account. If you do not know your company's ContentLink account administrator you may contact us emailing our Customer Support at [TACLSupport@teleatlas.com](mailto:TACLSupport@teleatlas.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.  
In order to ensure that all of your Identifying Information is correct and up-to-date, at any time you may email us at [webmanager@teleatlas.com](mailto:webmanager@teleatlas.com) and request your Identifying Information. Please include your User name and Password in any request for your Identifying Information. You may then access, review and update your Identifying Information that we have already collected.

**6\. Lost or Stolen Information**

You must promptly notify us if your credit card, User name or Password is lost, stolen or used without permission. Please contact us at [webmanager@teleatlas.com](mailto:webmanager@teleatlas.com). In such an event, we will cancel that credit card number, User Name or Password and update our records accordingly.

**7\. Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with Tele Atlas, you can contact us at [webmanager@teleatlas.com](mailto:webmanager@teleatlas.com).  
Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out' of having your Identifying Information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information.  For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [webmanager@teleatlas.com](mailto:webmanager@teleatlas.com).  We offer an opportunity to opt-out of certain communications on our newsletter and promotional communications, or you may contact us at 1-800-331-7881 or [webmanager@teleatlas.com](mailto:webmanager@teleatlas.com) or postal mail to the address listed above to opt-out.

_Email-A-Friend_   
If you choose to use our referral service to email a page about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address.  We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site.  Tele Atlas stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email

Your friend may contact us at [webmanager@teleatlas.com](mailto:webmanager@teleatlas.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

_AddToAny_ :  
We use the addtoany widget that allows you to email your friend about the site by sending them a one time email.  Tele Atlas does not collect or store any of this information, please read the privacy policy of AddToAny as it governs the collection and use of this information.  This widget also allows you to log into any of your social networking sites in order to share links to Tele Atlas.

_Agents/Service Providers  _   
We use other third parties such as a shipping company to fulfill orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services.  
Jobdigtracker.com is a service provider and all information collected and used is governed by their privacy statement. Jobdigtracker does share the information back with Tele Atlas for the purpose of Tele Atlas deciding who is a good candidate to interview for a specific Job.  Tele Atlas only uses that information for the purpose of determining who is qualified for the job and interviewing them.  
Tele Atlas does not share, sell, rent or trade PII with third parties for their promotional purposes.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at [webmanager@teleatlas.com](mailto:webmanager@teleatlas.com).

The security of your personal information is important to us.  When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

_Third Party Cookies_

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, and service providers is covered by their privacy statement.  We do not have access or control over these cookies.  Our partners, affiliates, and service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site and/or the shopping cart, etc.

**Customer Success Stories  
**We post customer success stories on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information.  We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the success story to post their name along with their testimonial.

If you use a bulletin board, blog, or chat room on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

You have the ability to send private messages to users within the developerlinl.teleatlas.com portal.  Please be aware that any personal information you choose to share within the private messages may be used by the recipient.  Tele Atlas has no access or control over what you choose to share with other users. We highly recommend that you do not share more information than is reasonably necessary.

Users of the developerlink.teleatlas.com portion of the site have the ability to create a profile of themselves.  Please be aware that your profile may be viewed by others, please do not publish any information about yourself that you do not wish for other users of this forum to see. You must be rated before users are able to view your profile.  Being rated on your forum posts determines whether or not your profile is viewable by others.

The TRUSTe program only covers information that is collected through this Web site, and **does not** cover information that may be collected through any software downloaded from this Web site.  
Tele Atlas is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program.  TRUSTe is an independent, organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices.  This privacy statement covers the Web site [www.teleatlas.com](http://www.teleatlas.com/) and [www.geographic.com/contentlink](http://www.geographic.com/contentlink)   Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Phil O'Donnell at 1-800-331-7881.  If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at [http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url](http://http//watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=)=.  TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns.

Tele Atlas complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union

Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

To learn more about our advertising company's use of clear gifs, please go to [www.doubleclick.com](http://www.doubleclick.com/)

**Tele Atlas North America, Inc.  
11 Lafayette Street  
Lebanon, New Hampshire 03766  
1-800-331-7881  

Last Updated on 01/19/2010
